Guide to the American Song Sheets Collection, circa 1830s-1920s, bulk 1850s-1880s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- American Song Sheets, circa 1850s-1880s, (4 boxes, items 1-1608)
  - Sheridan! Cavalry Sheridan! (Box 3, Item 1443)
  - Soldier's Farewell (Box 3, Item 1444)
  - Just Before the Battle, Mother (Box 3, Item 1445)
  - The Battle of Gettysburg (Box 3, Item 1446)
  - Love Thee (Box 3, Item 1447)
  - The Battle of Winchester (Box 3, Item 1448)
  - I Would Not Die in Spring (Box 3, Item 1449)
  - How Sheridan Whipped Longstreet (Box 3, Item 1450)
  - The Nation is Weeping (Box 3, Item 1451)
  - Brother, Tell Me of the Battle (Box 3, Item 1452)
  - Susannah Don't You Cry (Box 3, Item 1453)
  - Was My Brother in the Battle? (Box 3, Item 1454)
  - How Sherman's Veterans Took Atlanta (Box 3, Item 1455)
  - The Soldier's Farewell to his Bride (Box 3, Item 1456)
  - The Banner of the Free (Box 3, Item 1457)
  - Kingdom Coming (Box 3, Item 1458)
  - Victory at Last (Box 3, Item 1459)
  - Parody on the Cottage by the Sea (Box 3, Item 1460)
  - The Conscript's Lay (Box 3, Item 1461)
  - The Jockey Hat and Feather (Box 3, Item 1462)
  - Jack Lannigan's Wake (Box 3, Item 1463)
  - Brave Boys (Box 3, Item 1464)
  - Kitty Wells (Box 3, Item 1465)
  - The Nation Mourns (Box 3, Item 1466)
  - The Nation Mourns (Box 3, Item 1467)
  - Lannegan's Ball (Box 3, Item 1468)
  - Paddy Burke (Box 3, Item 1469)
  - Lorena (Box 3, Item 1470)
  - Sheridan's "Early" Victory (Box 3, Item 1471)
  - Wait Till You Get It (Box 3, Item 1472)
  - Will Nobody Marry Me? (Box 3, Item 1473)
  - When I'm On a Distant Shore (Box 3, Item 1474)
  - The 195th Pennsylvania Volunteer (Box 3, Item 1475)
  - Annie Laurie (Box 3, Item 1476)
  - A Cheerful Song (Box 3, Item 1477)
  - General Logan, and the Fifteenth Army Corps (Box 3, Item 1478)
  - Nobody's Darling but Mine (Box 3, Item 1479)
  - Oh! Dem Golden Slippers (Box 3, Item 1480)
  - Farmer's Daughter (Box 3, Item 1481)
  - The Sailor's Grave (Box 3, Item 1482)
  - Sherman's March to the Sea (Box 3, Item 1483)
  - Whisper Softly, Mother's Dying (Box 3, Item 1484)
  - The Bells of Shandon (Box 3, Item 1485)
  - Woodman, Spare That Tree (Box 3, Item 1486)
  - Tis Hard to Give the Hand Where the Heart Can Never Be (Box 3, Item 1487)
  - Don't You Go, Tommy (Box 3, Item 1488)
  - Glove Flirtation (Box 3, Item 1489)
  - Drunkard's Lone Child (Box 3, Item 1490)
  - Pull for the Shore (Box 3, Item 1491)
  - I've No Mother Now, I'm Weeping (Box 3, Item 1492)
  - You May Look, But You Mustn't Touch (Box 3, Item 1493)
  - Mollie Darling (Box 3, Item 1494)
  - Old Wooden Rocker (Box 3, Item 1495)
  - I'll Remember You, Love, In My Prayers (Box 3, Item 1496)
  - Where the Grass Grows Green (Box 3, Item 1497)
  - A Flower from Mother's Grave (Box 3, Item 1498)
  - Take Me Back to Home and Mother (Box 3, Item 1499)
  - The Two Orphans (Box 3, Item 1500)
  - Old Man's Drunk Again (Box 4, Item 1501)
  - Carry Me Back to Old Virginny (Box 4, Item 1502)
  - The Girl I Left Behind Me (Box 4, Item 1503)
  - Her Bright Smile Haunts Me Still (Box 4, Item 1504)
  - Silver Threads Among the Gold (Box 4, Item 1505)
  - She Never Blamed Him Never (Box 4, Item 1506)
  - You've Been a Friend to Me (Box 4, Item 1507)
  - The Gray Hairs of my Mother (Box 4, Item 1508)
  - Blue-Eyed Nelly (Box 4, Item 1509)
  - Wandering Refugee (Box 4, Item 1510)
  - Little Old Cabin in the Lane (Box 4, Item 1511)
  - We Parted by the River Side (Box 4, Item 1512)
  - The Wearing of the Green (Box 4, Item 1513)
  - When You and I Were Young, Maggie (Box 4, Item 1514)
  - Killarney (Box 4, Item 1515)
  - Widow in the Cottage by the Sea (Box 4, Item 1516)
  - The Keyhole in the Door (Box 4, Item 1517)
  - The Dying Girl's Message (Box 4, Item 1518)
  - Sour Krout (Box 4, Item 1519)
  - Juice of the Forbidden Fruit (Box 4, Item 1520)
  - A Knot of Blue and Gray (Box 4, Item 1521)
  - The Captain With His Whiskers (Box 4, Item 1522)
  - Napoleon's Farewell to Paris (Box 4, Item 1523)
  - The Farmer's Boy (Box 4, Item 1524)
  - A Warrior Bold (Box 4, Item 1525)
  - Rosalie, the Prarie Flower (Box 4, Item 1526)
  - Dreaming of Home and Mother (Box 4, Item 1527)
  - The Dying Nun (Box 4, Item 1528)
  - An Irishman's Toast (Box 4, Item 1529)
  - Who's At My Bedroom Window? (Box 4, Item 1530)
  - Watch on the Rhine (Box 4, Item 1531)
  - The Boston Burglar (Box 4, Item 1532)
  - Rocky Road to Dublin (Box 4, Item 1533)
  - Grant's Trip Around the World (Box 4, Item 1534)
  - The Arkansas Traveler (Box 4, Item 1535)
  - Joe Bowers (Box 4, Item 1536)
  - Down in a Coal Mine (Box 4, Item 1537)
  - Uncle Tom's Lament (Box 4, Item 1538)
  - Mantle So Green (Box 4, Item 1539)
  - McDonald's Return to Glenco (Box 4, Item 1540)
  - The Blackbird (Box 4, Item 1541)
  - I Had but Fifty Cents (Box 4, Item 1542)
  - Bonny Bunch of Roses (Box 4, Item 1543)
  - Barbara Allan (Box 4, Item 1544)
  - Pull Down the Blind (Box 4, Item 1545)
  - Willy Reilly (Box 4, Item 1546)
  - Barney McCoy (Box 4, Item 1547)
  - You'll Miss Me When I'm Gone (Box 4, Item 1548)
  - The Whip-Poor-Will's Song (Box 4, Item 1549)
  - My Dear Savannah Home (Box 4, Item 1550)
  - Sweet Belle Mahone (Box 4, Item 1551)
  - Soldier's Farewell (Box 4, Item 1552)
  - I'm Getting a Big Boy Now (Box 4, Item 1553)
  - One Pound Two (Box 4, Item 1554)
  - Yellow Rose of Texas (Box 4, Item 1555)
  - Six Feet of Earth (Box 4, Item 1556)
  - Banks of Brandywine (Box 4, Item 1557)
  - Stokes' Verdict (Box 4, Item 1558)
  - Do Not Heed Her Warning (Box 4, Item 1559)
  - Boys, Keep Away from Girls (Box 4, Item 1560)
  - They All Do It (Box 4, Item 1561)
  - I'se Gwine Back to Dixie (Box 4, Item 1562)
  - The Butcher Boy (Box 4, Item 1563)
  - Broken Down (Box 4, Item 1564)
  - Sweet Sunny South (Box 4, Item 1565)
  - Only Been Down to the Club (Box 4, Item 1566)
  - Little Footsteps (Box 4, Item 1567)
  - Somebody's Coming When the Dew-drops Fall (Box 4, Item 1568)
  - Come Into the Garden, Maud (Box 4, Item 1569)
  - Over the Hills to the Poor-house (Box 4, Item 1570)
  - Tenting on the Old Camp-Ground (Box 4, Item 1571)
  - I Cannot Sing the Old Songs (Box 4, Item 1572)
  - Fisherman's Daughter (Box 4, Item 1573)
  - Shells of the Ocean (Box 4, Item 1574)
  - Driven from Home (Box 4, Item 1575)
  - Perished in the Snow (Box 4, Item 1576)
  - The Gipsy's Warning (Box 4, Item 1577)
  - The Faded Coat of Blue (Box 4, Item 1578)
  - The Cottage By the Sea (Box 4, Item 1579)
  - Where Was Moses When the Light Went Out? (Box 4, Item 1580)
  - Marching Through Georgia (Box 4, Item 1581)
  - Take This Letter to My Mother (Box 4, Item 1582)
  - Morning by the Bright Light (Box 4, Item 1583)
  - On de Oder Side of Jordon (Box 4, Item 1584)
  - Amber Tresses Tied in Blue (Box 4, Item 1585)
  - Heart Bowed Down (Box 4, Item 1586)
  - See That My Grave's Kept Green (Box 4, Item 1587)
  - An Appeal to the South (Box 4, Item 1588)
  - A New Song (Box 4, Item 1589)
  - A New Song (Box 4, Item 1590)
  - Parrott For Ever! (Box 4, Item 1591)
  - Jack At Home (Box 4, Item 1592)
  - A New Election Song (Box 4, Item 1593)
  - Triumphal Song (Box 4, Item 1594)
  - To the Independent Electors of the Newly Enfranchised Borough of Macclesfield (Box 4, Item 1595)
  - A New Election Song (Box 4, Item 1596)
  - A New Election Song (Box 4, Item 1597)
  - A New Election Song (Box 4, Item 1598)
  - A New Election Song (Box 4, Item 1599)
  - A New Song (Box 4, Item 1600)
  - Old Joe (Box 4, Item 1601)
  - When I Was Young and Fair (Box 4, Item 1602)
  - The Jolly Skiffsman (Box 4, Item 1603)
  - Lucy Long (Box 4, Item 1604)
  - When Sailing on de Ohio (Box 4, Item 1605)
  - Who's Dat Knocking at de Door (Box 4, Item 1606)
  - The Boatman of de Ohio (Box 4, Item 1607)
  - Burns and Highland Mary (Box 4, Item 1608)
- American Song Sheets (addition), circa 1850s-1880s, (18 folders, 212 items)
  Addition contains 212 Civil War and Reconstruction era song sheets published by prominent song sheet publishers of the period such as J. Andrews, A. W. Auner, Bell and Company, James D. Gray, Johnson and Company, Charles Magnus, H. de Marsan, T. M. Scroggy, St. Clair Smith, John T. Thorne, H. J. Wehman, and J. Wrigley. Song sheets in this addition have not been digitized.
  Song sheets in this addition are arranged by publisher name and alphabetically by song title within each publisher group.
  - Song sheets published by J. Andrews, (1 folder, 11 items)
    - Advice to Young Ladies and Oh, Say Not Woman's Heart is Bought (Box 4)
    - Am I Not Fondly Thine Own and I'll Remember Thee (Box 4)
    - Annie I Have Missed You (Box 4)
    - The City Beau (Box 4)
    - The Indian Warrior's Grave and Indian Hunter (Box 4)
    - The Lass That Loves a Sailor and the Lass For a Sailor (Box 4)
    - The Minute Gun at Sea and The Anchor's Weigh'd (Box 4)
    - Nancy Gray (Box 4)
    - Oh! Silber Shining Moon (Box 4)
    - Sprig of Shillelah (Box 4)
    - To The One I Love (Box 4)
  - Song sheets published by A. W. Auner, (1 folder, 8 items)
    - Uncle Sam's Farm (Box 4)
    - Apple of My Eye (Box 4)
    - Bacon and Greens (Box 4)
    - One Black Joe (Box 4)
    - Old Log Cabin On The Hill (Box 4)
    - Papa Where's My Mama Gone? (Box 4)
    - Parrot and the Parson (Box 4)
    - Sally Horner 'Round the Corner (Box 4)
  - Song sheets published by Bell and Company, (1 folder, 9 items)
    - All Among the Roses or, Sweet Camilla May (Box 4)
    - Behind the Scenes (Box 4)
    - The Day When You'll Forget Me (Box 4)
    - The Day When You'll Forget Me (Box 4)
    - First She Would and Then She Wouldn't or O You Naughty, Naughty Man! (Box 4)
    - Little German Band (Box 4)
    - New Years Song, 1876 (Box 4)
    - Since Mary Ann Learned how to Dance the Tra-la-la-loo (Box 4)
    - Tommy, Make Room for Your Uncle (Box 4)
  - Song sheets published by James D. Gay, (1 folder, 3 items)
    - How Sherman's Veterans Took Atlanta (Box 4)
    - Keystone Brigade (Box 4)
    - Keystone Brigade (Box 4)
  - Song sheets published by Johnson and Co., (1 folder, 5 items)
    - Birds' Ball (Box 4)
    - Good-bye John (Box 4)
    - I Cannot Sing the Old Songs (Box 4)
    - Maggie's Secret (Box 4)
    - Give Us Back Our Old Commander (Box 4)
  - Song sheets published by Charles Magnus, (1 folder, 3 items)
    - How to Close the War (Box 4)
    - Mother, I've Come Home to Die (Box 4)
    - Weep Not, Comrades, For Me (Box 4)
  - Song sheets published by H. de Marsan, (6 folders, 109 items)
    - All's For the Best (Box 4)
    - The American Boy (Box 4)
    - Anyone Will Do and Mine Pipe and Cup (Box 4)
    - Be a Good Boy and Take Care of Yourself (Box 4)
    - The Bold Privateer (Box 4)
    - Bonaparte's Farewell (Box 4)
    - Bonaparte's Farewell (Box 4)
    - The Bonny Light horseman (Box 4)
    - Bucanier's Bride (Box 4)
    - Bummers, Come and Meet Us (Box 4)
    - The Butcher Boy (Box 4)
    - Captain De Wellington Boots (Box 4)
    - Carrie Lee (Box 4)
    - Charcoal Man (Box 4)
    - The Charming Woman (Box 4)
    - The Charming Woman (Box 4)
    - Come Home Father (Box 4)
    - Come Where My Love Lies Dreaming (Box 4)
    - Cottage by the Hill (Box 4)
    - Couldn't Stand the Press (Box 4)
    - Cross-Keen Lawn (Box 4)
    - Cum Plung Gum (Box 4)
    - Dear Mary, Come Back (Box 4)
    - Do Not Heed Her Warning (Box 4)
    - Do Not Heed Her Warning (Box 4)
    - A Dollar or Two (Box 4)
    - The Farmer's Boy (Box 4)
    - Father Macshane (Box 4)
    - The Garden Gate (Box 4)
    - Gay is the life of a Fighting Amerykin (Box 4)
    - Go Where Glory Waits Thee (Box 4)
    - The Grave of Banaparte (Box 4)
    - Happy Land of Canaan (Box 4)
    - Hard Times (Box 4)
    - Homeward-Bound and Thou Hast Cast Off the Heart (Box 4)
    - Hot Codlins (Box 4)
    - I Promised I Never Would Leave Her (Box 4)
    - I Promised I Never Would Leave Her (Box 4)
    - I Stood Amid the Glittering Throng (Box 4)
    - I'am Not Myself At All (Box 4)
    - I'll Ask My Mother and let you know Next Sunday Afternoon (Box 4)
    - I'm Lonely Since My Mother Died (Box 4)
    - It's Wonderful How We Do It, But We Do (Box 4)
    - Johnny Schmoker (Box 4)
    - Joseph Tuck (Box 4)
    - Land of the West (Box 4)
    - The Landlord's Pet (Box 4)
    - The Lass That Loves a Sailor and the Lass For a Sailor (Box 4)
    - Laughing Song (Box 4)
    - The Liberty Pole (Box 4)
    - Linger Not, Darling (Box 4)
    - Little Bare-Foot (Box 4)
    - A Little More Cider (Box 4)
    - Little Topsy's Song (Box 4)
    - Lovely Sweet Banks of the Suir (Box 4)
    - Loving Well and Dearly! (Box 4)
    - Maria, the Dustman's Wife (Box 4)
    - The Monitor and Merrimac (Box 4)
    - Nettie Moore (Box 4)
    - Nettie Moore (Box 4)
    - Oh Let me go to my Home Again (Box 4)
    - Oh! Write Me a Song of My Father (Box 4)
    - The Old Mountain Tree (Box 4)
    - One Foot in the Stirrup (Box 4)
    - Ould Ireland You're My Darlin' (Box 4)
    - Our Country's Flag (Box 4)
    - Our Glorious Flag (Box 4)
    - Our Grand-father's Days (Box 4)
    - Our Union (Box 4)
    - Our Yankee Monitor (Box 4)
    - The Outlaw (Box 4)
    - Paddy Murphy's Auction (Box 4)
    - The Phoenix Society (Box 4)
    - The Real Perfect Cure (Box 4)
    - The Poor Little Soldier's Boy (Box 4)
    - The Pretty Ballet Girl (Box 4)
    - The Pretty Ballet Girl (Box 4)
    - Pulling Hard Against the Stream (Box 4)
    - Rosalie the Prairie Flower (Box 4)
    - The Rose of Allendale (Box 4)
    - Row, Row (Box 4)
    - Souverneen Deelish Eileen Oge (Box 4)
    - Souverneen Deelish Eileen Oge (Box 4)
    - Sharon Lawn (Box 4)
    - She Danced Like a Fairy (Box 4)
    - The New Skedaddle Song (Box 4)
    - Smiggey McGuirrel (Box 4)
    - The Soldier's Return and I Am Wandering All Alone (Box 4)
    - The Song My Mother Used to Sing (Box 4)
    - The Southern Cross (Box 4)
    - Sweet Evelina (Box 4)
    - The Tilt-skirt (Box 4)
    - Tis Midnight 'Hour and Oft in the Stilly Night (Box 4)
    - To a Brother Figting for the Union (Box 4)
    - Tom Bowling (Box 4)
    - Uncle Snow (Box 4)
    - Uncle Tommy (Box 4)
    - Under the Gaslight, or Poor Little Laura (Box 4)
    - The Union Boys (Box 4)
    - The Union Volunteers (Box 4)
    - Victory at Last (Box 4)
    - A Voice from Ellsworth (Box 4)
    - War-Song of the Union (Box 4)
    - We Meet by Chance (Box 4)
    - When the Boys Come Home (Box 4)
    - Will Watch (Box 4)
    - Wille's on the Dark Blue Sea (Box 4)
    - The Wood-Robin (Box 4)
    - Yankee Land (Box 4)
  - Song sheets published by T. M. Scroggy, (1 folder, 6 items) (Box 4)
    - Ancient Rams No. 2 of Southwark (Box 4)
    - Ancient Rams No. 2 of Southwark (Box 4)
    - The Bold Privateer (Box 4)
    - The Coal Black Steed (Box 4)
    - Franklin Hose Song (Box 4)
    - I'm Off For Charleston (Box 4)
  - Song sheets published by St. Clair Smith, (1 folder, 2 items)
    - Birdie Genay (Box 4)
    - Rebecca, the Dearest Girl on Earth (Box 4)
  - Song sheets published by John T. Thorne, (1 folder, 1 item)
    - Juice of the Forbidden Fruit (Box 4)
      Rare early (first?) version of a popular American drinking song, in which Adam and Eve appear as the first tipplers, “and ever since then, all manner of men/ The lame, the blind, and the mute/ Our bankers and clerks, politicians and turks/ Drink the juice of the Forbidden Fruit.” This chorus is followed by a litany of public figures who imbibe, including Edwin Booth, [Henry Ward] Beecher, President Arthur, Frank James, Bob Ford, Oscar Wild[e], General Grant, Roscoe Conkling, and [James G.] Blaine. The names varied over time, but the song remained in circulation for many decades and was recorded by folklorist Alan Lomax in the 1950s. Lomax identified it as originating in the Ozarks, but by the turn of the century the song was sufficiently widespread to make an appearance in Jack London’s story “The Man on the Trail, A Klondike Christmas,” published in the Overland Monthly in January 1899.
  - Song sheets published by H. J. Wehman, (2 folders, 36 items)
    - Ben Bolt (Box 4)
    - Darling Nelly Gray (Box 4)
    - Do Not Heed Her Warning (Box 4)
    - Do They Think of Me at Home? (Box 4)
    - Do They Think of Me at Home? (Box 4)
    - Ever of Thee (Box 4)
    - Gathering Shells from the Sea Shore (Box 4)
    - The Gipsy's Warning (Box 4)
    - The Hazel-Dell (Box 4)
    - Hold the Fort (Box 4)
    - John Brown Song (Box 4)
    - Johnny, Get Your Gun (Box 4)
    - Juanita (Box 4)
    - Just Before the Battle, Mother (Box 4)
    - Listen to the Mocking-Bird (Box 4)
    - Marching Through Georgia (Box 4)
    - Morning by the Bright Light (Box 4)
    - My Dream of Love is O'er (Box 4)
    - My Old Kentucky Home (Box 4)
    - Nancy Lee (Box 4)
    - Nelly was a Lady (Box 4)
    - Now I Lay Me Down to Sleep (Box 4)
    - One-Horse Open Sleigh (Jingle Bells) (Box 4)
    - Pop Goes the Weasel (Box 4)
    - Roll On, Silver Moon (Box 4)
    - See-Saw! (Box 4)
    - Shoo, fly! Don't Bodder Me (Box 4)
    - Silver Threads Among the Gold (Box 4)
    - Sword of Bunker Hill (Box 4)
    - Take Back the Heart (Box 4)
    - Thou Hast Learned to Love Another (Box 4)
    - Thou Hast Wounded the Spirit That Loved Thee (Box 4)
    - Tramp, Tramp, Tramp! (Box 4)
    - Wait Till the Clouds Roll By (Box 4)
    - Where the Sweet Magnolia Grows (Box 4)
    - Where was Moses when the Light Went Out (Box 4)
  - Song sheets published by J. Wrigley, (1 folders, 1 item)
    - The Rollicking Rams (Box 4)
  - Song sheets published by unknown publishers, (1 folder, 19 items)
    - The Bold Engineer (Box 4)
    - The Bonnie Blue Flag and Dixie (Box 4)
    - Columbia, The Gem of the Ocean (Box 4)
    - The Dead Soldier: A Pathetic Incident of the Battle of Antietam (Box 4)
    - For Home and Country (Box 4)
    - Good Will Hose Song (Box 4)
    - In Happy Moments (Box 4)
    - In Memory of Nath'l Bloodgood (Box 4)
    - It's a Long Way to Tipperary (Box 4)
    - John Harrolson (Box 4)
    - Keep Your Powder Dry (Box 4)
    - On the Battle of Fort Donelson (Box 4)
    - The Organ Grinder (Box 4)
    - Poe (Box 4)
    - Sheridan's Ride (Box 4)
    - Sword of Bunker Hill (Box 4)
    - There is Life in Old Maryland Yet (Box 4)
    - Zu Meinim Achtzigsten Jahrestage (Box 4)
    - Zur Vierter Konvention: Des Deutsch-Amerikanischen National Bundes der Ger. Staaten von Amerika (Box 4)
- Oversize American Song Sheets, (1 box, items 1719-1741)
  - Our Opinion; A Hit At These Times (Box 5, Item 1719)
  - All Spice; or Spice for All (Box 5, Item 1720)
  - Ballad of the Great Fight (Box 5, Item 1721)
  - The Marylander at Manassas (Box 5, Item 1722)
  - Jeff Davis' Last Proclamation (Box 5, Item 1723)
  - Chivalrous C.S.A! (Box 5, Item 1724)
  - The Union Yankee Doodle (Box 5, Item 1725)
  - Lines for the Paroled Prisoners (Box 5, Item 1726)
  - The Virginia's Knocking Around (Box 5, Item 1727)
  - William Price (Box 5, Item 1728)
  - William Price (Box 5, Item 1729)
  - Our Opinion (Box 5, Item 1730)
  - The Carrier's Address to the Patrons and Friends of the Flag of the Union (Box 5, Item 1731)
  - Lines in Memory of the Philadelphia Volunteer Refreshment Saloon (Box 5, Item 1732)
  - Lines in Memory of the Philadelphia Volunteer Refreshment Saloon (Box 5, Item 1733)
  - A Collection of Songs (Box 5, Item 1734)
  - Funny Songster (Box 5, Item 1735)
  - Christmas Address! (Box 5, Item 1736)
  - A Picture of the Graham P. Society, of Washington College, Va., Represented in a Dream: (Box 5, Item 1737)
  - New Year's Address (Box 5, Item 1738)
  - Prison Song (Box 5, Item 1739)
  - A Ballade (Box 5, Item 1740)
  - The Black Decree, & c. (Box 5, Item 1741)
- Confederate Pamphlets, (items 1719-1741)
  Song sheets in this series are housed in the Confederate Pamphlets collection. Call numbers are listed.
  - The American Rebels (Box 5, Item 1609)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 95
  - The Dead of Alabama (Box 5, Item 1610)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 96
  - Song of the South! General Davis (Box 5, Item 1611)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 97
  - God and Liberty! (Box 5, Item 1612)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 98
  - Graves For the Invaders. (Box 5, Item 1613)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 99
  - Hurrah for Dixie! (Box 5, Item 1614)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 100
  - Lines On the Death of the Confederate Gen. Albert Sidney Johnston, of KY. (Box 5, Item 1615)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 101
  - The Merry Little Soldier (Box 5, Item 1616)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 102
  - Cotton is King (Box 5, Item 1617)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 103
  - The Southern Girl's Song (Box 5, Item 1618)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 104
  - Awake in Dixie. (Box 5, Item 1619)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 105
  - Ode on the Meeting of the Southern Congress (Box 5, Item 1620)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 106
  - Maryland in Chains (Box 5, Item 1621)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 107
  - The Battle of Manassas (Box 5, Item 1622)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 109
  - Audax omnia perpeti Gens Lincolna ruit per vititum nefas. (Box 5, Item 1623)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 117
  - Land of the South! (Box 5, Item 1624)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 118
  - The Retreat of the Sixty Thousand Lincoln Troops. (Box 5, Item 1625)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 119
  - Southern Yankee Doodle (Box 5, Item 1626)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 120
  - Good News From Dixie. (Box 5, Item 1627)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 121
  - Great Big Bethel Fight. (Box 5, Item 1628)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 122
  - The Battle of the Stoves-pipes. (Box 5, Item 1629)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 123
  - The Saucy Little Turtle. (Box 5, Item 1630)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 125
  - If You Belong to Dixie's Land. (Box 5, Item 1631)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 129
  - The Race in Dixie. (Box 5, Item 1632)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 130
  - Siege of Charleston. (Box 5, Item 1633)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 131
  - Our Own Dixie. (Box 5, Item 1634)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 133
  - Run, Yank, or Die! (Box 5, Item 1635)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 134
  - The Guerrillas (Box 5, Item 1636)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 141
  - The Guerillas (Box 5, Item 1637)
    Call Number: Conf Pam qo # 142
  - The Battle of Drainesville (Box 5, Item 1638)
    Call Number: Conf Pam q # 757
  - The Confederate Flag (Box 5, Item 1639)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 732
  - The Flag of Secession. (Box 5, Item 1640)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 733
  - General Beauregard (Box 5, Item 1641)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 734
  - God Help Kentucky! (Box 5, Item 1642)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 735
  - Hark! O'er the Southern Hills. (Box 5, Item 1643)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 736
  - Hurrah for the South! Hurrah. (Box 5, Item 1644)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 737
  - The Last Race of the Rail-Splitter. (Box 5, Item 1645)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 738
  - The Lone Star Camp Song. (Box 5, Item 1646)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 739
  - The Maryland Martyrs. (Box 5, Item 1647)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 740
  - North Carolina. A Call to Arms!!! (Box 5, Item 1648)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 741
  - Address to her Maryland Lover, by a Virginia Girl (Box 5, Item 1649)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 742
  - Rally Round the Standard Boys. (Box 5, Item 1650)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 743
  - The Rebel's Retort. (Box 5, Item 1651)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 744
  - To Miss Harriot Pinckney (Box 5, Item 1652)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 745
  - The Song of the Exile. (Box 5, Item 1653)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 746
  - Volunteer Mess Song. (Box 5, Item 1654)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 747
  - An Impromptu. (Box 5, Item 1655)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 767
  - The Battle of Bulls Run. (Box 5, Item 1656)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 768
  - Beauregard. (Box 5, Item 1657)
    Call Number: Conf Pam # 769
  - Rally Round the Flag. (Box 5, Item 1658)